Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
The year is 2015 A.D.
As of 12:30 PM today, a special state
of emergency has been declared
for the Kanto and Chubu regions
surrounding the Tokai district.
All residents must evacuate to their
designated shelters immediately.
Repeating: As of 12:30 PM today,
All Lines Stopped
the Kanto and Chubu regions
surrounding the Tokai district
have been declared to be under
a state of emergency.
All residents must evacuate...
Why did I have to lose sight of him now?
Oh, man!
Shinji Ikari
Due to the special emergency,
all lines are currently unavailable.
It's no use.
I shouldn't have come here after all.
To Shinji
I'll be coming to get you,
so wait for me.
Attention here please!!
Well, I guess we won't be meeting here.
Can't be helped. I'll go to a shelter.
Estimated Path
The unidentified mobile object is still
advancing on our position.
We've got visual confirmation.
I'm putting it on the main screen.
It's been fifteen years, hasn't it?
Yes, there's no doubt.
It's an Angel.
EPISODE ONE
ANGEL ATTACK
Every missile hit the target!
I'm sorry! Thanks for waiting!
The target is still operational.
It's still heading towards New Tokyo-3.
The Air Defense Force doesn't have
the firepower to stop it!
Hit it with everything we've got!
Mobilize all of Atsugi and Iruma as well!
Don't hold anything back!
Destroy the target at any cost!
Why?! That was a direct hit!
The tank battalion's been annihilated.
Guided missiles and artillery
have no effect either.
It's no good! We'll never get anywhere
with the firepower we've got!
Is it an AT field after all?
Yes. Conventional weapons are
useless against Angels.
I understand. We'll activate it as planned.
Hey, don't tell me...
They're going to use an N2 mine?!
Get down!
We did it!
Sorry, but it looks like you won't be
getting a shot at it.
Shock wave approaching.
Are you all right?
Yeah, but my mouth is full of dirt.
That's okay. Now then, here we go!
One, two!
There.
Thanks for the hand. I really appreciate it.
Thank you too, Miss Katsuragi.
Just Misato is fine.
I'm glad we've met at last, Shinji Ikari.
Yeah...
What's the target's status?
We're unable to confirm due to
all the EMP interference.
You saw the size of the explosion. It's over.
Sensors restored.
We've got an energy reading
at the explosion's epicenter!
What the hell?!
Visual display restored.
That was our last resort.
How can this be?
Damned monster!
Yes. Don't worry about it.
His safety is my top priority,
so could you get a car train ready for us?
A direct one.
Right.
Well, I volunteered to pick him up,
so I'll make sure he gets there. See ya!
Man, this sucks! I just had my car restored
and it's a total wreck already!
33 more loan payments to go,
plus the cost of repairs.
And look! My best dress has been ruined!
Um, Miss Misato...
And I was looking and feeling so nice.
Excuse me, Misato?
What?
Are you sure you can just take those?
Never mind about that!
It's an emergency, and we need
a working car right now, right?
And I'm an international government
official, after all,
so everything's going to be
perfectly fine, okay?
I don't think anyone will buy that.
You're no fun. You look cute,
but you're kind of a cold fish.
You think so?
Oh, did I upset you?
Sorry about that! You are a boy, after all.
And you're pretty childish for your age.
As we predicted, it's regenerating itself.
If it couldn't, it wouldn't be
a practical autonomous weapon.
Impressive. It appears it can even upgrade
its own operational functions.
And it seems to have gotten smarter.
It's only a matter of time before
it resumes attacking.
The gates are now closing.
Please stand clear.
The special duty organization Nerv?
Now departing.
Yes, it's a secret organization under
the control of the United Nations.
This is the C-22 Special Express
departing directly for G33-1.
That's where my father is, right?
Well, yeah.
Do you know what he does?
This train will bypass all other stations.
Please stand back.
My teacher told me his work is vital
for the protection of the human race.
From this point forward, command of this
operation will be entrusted to you.
Show us what you're capable of.
Yes, Sir.
Ikari, we will admit that our weapons
have no effect on the target.
But are you sure you can beat this thing?
It's what Nerv was created for.
Let's hope you're correct.
The target is still stationary.
Our intercept system is currently
7.5% operational.
So, even the UN forces have retired.
What are you going to do?
I intend to activate Unit 01.
Unit 01? But we have no pilot.
That's not a problem. Another spare
will be delivered soon.
Are you taking me to my father?
Yes. Pretty much.
Father...
Oh, that's right. Did you get
an ID card from your father?
Yes.
Here it is.
Thanks.
Come.
Gendo Ikari
Then read this.
Welcome to Nerv
Nerv...
My father's agency.
Am I going to work for them too?
Of course.
He wouldn't have sent me a letter unless
he needed me for something.
I see. So you don't get along with your father.
It's the same with me.
Awesome!
It's a real Geo-Front!
That's right.
This is our secret base.
Nerv Headquarters.
This is the key to rebuilding our world.
A fortress for all mankind.
That's strange. Isn't this the right way?
This is why I hate wearing skirts here.
But where the heck did Ritsuko go?
I'm sorry. I'm just not used to this place yet.
We passed this spot just a little while ago.
But don't worry about it.
They make these systems
to be used, you know.
Would the head of Project E,
Technical Department Division 1,
Dr. Ritsuko Akagi, Dr. Ritsuko Akagi,
please contact Captain Misato Katsuragi
of Operations, Division 1, immediately.
I don't believe it.
She got lost again, didn't she?
Uh, hiya, Ritsuko.
What were you doing, Captain Katsuragi?
We're short on both time
and manpower, you know.
Sorry!
So this is the boy?
Right. According to the Marduk report,
he's the Third Child.
I'm glad to meet you.
Huh? Sure.
He's just like his father.
Like how he's unendearing.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Their first meeting in over three years.
Vice Commander, the target
has started moving again.
Right. All personnel, assume
battle stations, Level One.
Repeat. All personnel, assume
Prepare for ground-unit interception.
Here we go.
It sounds pretty serious.
So, how's Unit 01 doing?
It's currently in refrigeration,
using the B-type equipment.
Does it really work?
It's never worked before, right?
The possibility of activation is 0.000000001%.
We call it, pathetically enough,
the O-9 System.
Does that mean it doesn't work?
Oh, don't be insulting. It's not zero.
Well, it's just a number.
Anyway, it's a bit too late to be saying,
"Sorry, it didn't work".
Huh? It's completely dark.
A face? A giant robot?
You won't find this in the manual.
This is mankind's ultimate
multipurpose decisive weapon,
the synthetic human Evangelion, Unit 01.
Built in absolute secrecy,
it is mankind's trump card.
Is this part of what my father's been doing?
Correct.
It's been a while.
Father...
We're moving out!
Moving out?! Unit 00's still in
cryo-stasis, isn't it?
You're not planning to use Unit 01?!
There's no other way.
Hold on! Rei can't do it yet, can she?
We've got no pilot!
One's just been delivered.
Are you serious?
Shinji Ikari...
Yes?
You will pilot it.
But even Rei Ayanami took seven months
to synchronize with her Eva.
It's impossible for him to do it!
He just got here!
He just has to sit in the seat.
We don't expect more than that.
But...
Repelling that Angel is our ultimate priority.
To do that, we have no choice but to put
aboard the Eva whomever has the chance
to synchronize with it, no matter how slight.
I believe you know that, Captain Katsuragi.
I suppose...
Father, why did you send for me?
You know exactly why.
So, you're asking me to take this thing
and fight that thing?
That's right.
No way! Why are you doing this now?!
I thought you didn't need me!
I called you because I have a need for you.
Why me?
Because no one else can.
No, I can't...
I've never even seen anything
like this before! I can't do this!
You will be instructed.
But there's no way I can do this!
I can't pilot it!
If you're going to pilot it, do it now
and quickly. If not, leave!
It must have detected our location.
Shinji, we don't have time.
Get into it.
No! I didn't come for this! This isn't fair!
Shinji, just why did you come here?
You mustn't run! Not from your father,
and most of all not from yourself.
I know that! But there's no way I can do it!
Fuyutsuki...
Wake up Rei.
Can we use her?
She isn't dead.
I understand.
Rei.
Yes?
Our spare is unusable. You will do it again.
Yes, Sir.
Reconfigure Unit 01's system to Rei,
then re-activate!
Roger. Call off the present work,
and begin re-activation.
I knew it. I'm not needed after all.
Watch out!
The Eva moved!
What's going on?!
It broke the right arm restraint!
No, that's impossible!
It didn't even have an entry plug inserted!
There's no way it could have moved!
It reacted without any interface?!
Or was it protecting...
him?
We can do it.
I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away.
I mustn't run away.
I mustn't run away!
I'll do it.
I'll pilot it!
Cooling process, completed.
Right arm re-secured.
Cage contents now in position for docking.
Roger.
Signal terminator plug has been ejected.
Roger. Inserting entry plug.
Direct hydro-transmission system,
connection prepared.
Plug fixed in place.
First stage connection initiated.
Filling the entry plug.
What is this stuff?
Don't worry. Once your lungs
are filled with LCL,
your blood will be oxygenated directly.
You'll get used to it.
I feel nauseous.
Stop whining! You're a boy, aren't you?!
Connecting main power.
All circuits transmitting power.
Roger.
Commencing secondary contacts.
A-10 nerve connection, normal.
Set the thought configuration to Japanese.
All preliminary contacts established.
Performance nominal.
Bi-directional circuits are open.
Synchronization rate at 41.3%.
Amazing.
Harmonics are all normal.
No disturbances identified.
We can do it.
Prepare to launch!
Disengage primary lock bolts!
Disengage confirmed.
Disengaging the umbilical bridge.
Disengage secondary lock bolts.
Disengage primary restraints.
Likewise, disengage secondary restraints.
Release safety locks numbers
one through fifteen.
Release confirmed.
Currently, Unit 01's condition is free.
Internal batteries fully charged.
External battery outlet, normal.
Roger. Move Eva Unit 01
to the ejector pad.
Launch path is clear. All systems green.
Ready for launch.
Roger.
Can we really do this?
Of course.
Unless we defeat the Angels,
we have no future.
Ikari, you're really sure about this?
Launch!
Shinji, don't get killed out there.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Eva triumphs over the Angel!
However, that was just the beginning.
Shinji runs away from his father.
Misato's arrogance leads her
to try to save him.
Next Evangelion: "Unfamiliar Ceiling"
I'll give you fan service next time too!
UNFAMILIAR CEILING